I know webinars don't sound very sexy,
but putting one together in November,
I made
over $300,000 US,
and I think we spent $19,000
on acquiring those people in the first
place.
So I'm going to walk you through it real
basic, real simple, just to change your
mind on webinars really.
First thing you need to do
is create what I'd call a
presenting product. Now,
I have a live show that I've been
doing, it's about seven hours long,
where I've done the UK, Australia,
business
events where I go through every single
component.
I've also had paid gigs where I get paid a
fortune to go present for an hour or
two. So in my laptop,
I've got presentations
that I've put together, which never
really see the light of day after I've
presented them.
So I can create webinars with those just
by having that
slideshow there when I'm doing a webinar.
Also, you could just create one.
In the space of a few hours,
you could put together a very structured,
segmented
talk with visuals. And again,
my number one rule
when it comes to webinars or
presentations,
the slides should be there for you,
not so much them.
Because if your slides
are there for you
and they keep you on track and keep people
super engaged,
they're going to have a great time.
If you just try and make the slides for
them too much, you could just spend too
much time creating them.
First thing we need to do
is drive signups.
Now, the good news of this
is signups for a webinar
are easy because as far as the
squeeze, it's a good proposition.
"Hey,
I'm going to teach you something specific
for free for a few hours.
All I need is for you to attend
and give me your email address." Boom.
For them, it's very low effort
and low work.
It's not like you're giving them a
workbook or a course
or something to go through.
All they've got to do is go,
"Am I free at that time?
Can I put this on?
Yep, sure." Boom.
There's a transaction of value right
there.
So we spent $19,000, 5,000 email
addresses. I spent $19,000 on 5,000 email
address-- I should know maths. What
was my cost per email?
I could have just done
that in a calculator. $3.80 an email,
which can seem a lot.
Now, we presented the webinar,
20% of people showed up.
And you can see that can be depressing.
You go, "I've spent all this money,
and only 20%.
That's still 1,000 people." So I
presented, it was two hours long.
Now, just before going live,
I created a scheduled YouTube video.
So you go into YouTube,
I'm going to do it live on this date,
et cetera.
That creates a URL
that I could send to all the attendees.
It only went out via email.
So it only went to people, "Hey,
I'm going to be going
live." I sent them 24 hours before,
one hour before, I think about five, ten
minutes before. So you send those out.
Now, the 20% attendance rate is fine.
In the description, I created an offer.
It's a slight discount on my mentorship.
I put that in,
so everything's ready to go.
There are different streaming platforms
you can use.
If you're going to stream using a USB-C
cable, you're fine.
But if I was going to use this camera,
which is a Sony FX3, I need to manage the
bite rate. And to do so,
you need to use a third-party platform.
The one that I used was called Meld.
Maybe I'll do a walkthrough of
that into another video.
Let me know in the comments
if that's what you want.
And in essence,
that streams my camera to the back end of
YouTube so that when I'm
ready to go live, I click Live.
I then did a live stream for two hours
and 20
minutes to those people. I made sure
that within the presentation
or the webinar
that I was doing, every 10 minutes,
I presented the offer to the people
watching
because some people after half an hour
might be ready.
So if I can do a cadence for every 10
minutes to present the offer to someone,
someone might get to 20 minutes and go,
"You son of a bitch, I'm in." Might take
them 40 minutes, might take them an hour.
But if I wait till the very end,
you don't have to be a genius to imagine
the
retention graphs are going to drop off.
There are going to be people
that never get the offer.
So end of the call, hard sell,
probably offer the money-back guarantee
because
they're a super warm audience.
If they've just watched me for two hours
and 20
minutes,
they're not the type of people that
are going to join your course, do
nothing with it for six months,
and then come crying for their money back.
They're the type of people that
are ready to go, want to make change,
et cetera.
So I shut my laptop, go home, two hours,
20 minutes presenting, check my phone,
$26,000 US. Now, at that point, I
was like, "That's pretty good.
To make $26,000 US in two
and a half hours is good."
But then I said to the team,
"How much we spend on ads?" They say,
"19." I went, "Ugh, I've only made seven
grand this morning." Which again,
I know makes me sound like a fucking
dickhead,
but if you did two
and a half hours of work,
you'd be a little bit deflated.
And I thought to myself,
"Do you know what?
We're up and I've got all their contact
information." Because at this point, that
was only the people that had attended.
There's still the 4,000
that didn't make it to the webinar despite
signing up.
And that's just the importance of data.
So the rest of that month, we hammer
that list, and then we go public with
a Black Friday offer.
I'm going to give you the exact amount
now, just in case you
think I'm fibbing. All time. Jan, Feb,
$306,436 US. So it was a
$300,000 month.
It's my biggest month ever. Sorry,
we're good.
And it took some of them three weeks to
actually get converted.
So what I want you to think about is this.
Even though it's a webinar,
it's no different to everything
that I teach when it
comes to traditional marketing.
First of all,
get data from people on social media.
Now,
these people wouldn't have just given over
their email cold.
Even though it was paid ads,
you probably think, "Oh,
he just ran paid ads to a
cold audience,
and they gave me their email address." No.
The paid ads managed to activate the
audience of people who were in that
gap between being engaged enough to just
give me the email and ask or to download a
lead magnet. They were those people
that probably watched quite a few videos
and
still aren't that sure on me, which
are perfect candidates.
So the paid ads just extracted them,
squeezed the juices out of them a little
bit.
So we got them.
Then we had a lead magnet offer,
which the core
principle is what's in it for me.
Two hours,
20 minutes of fucking goodness is in
it for you for an email address.
Good exchange.
The next thing is we took it all to email
marketing.
The Black Friday offer,
the follow-up offer, the people
that didn't make the
webinar,
all those people got hit with an offer
through email marketing.
That email marketing sent them to a
bespoke landing page, which
was a standalone
page built just for that webinar.
And then we converted them across the
month to
have a 300K month,
which meant I decided I'm getting a sauna
and an ice bath in my
garden,
and I'm going to get some nice decking for
it.
And I also built a fantastic outdoor
shower,
which now I've kind of got a problem
where I don't like showering indoors
anymore.
And yeah,
also paid off a chunk of my mortgage.
But anyway, that's how the webinars work.
They work exactly the same as everything
else.
The webinar is just one of many tools on
your belt.
I want you to imagine you've got this
metaphorical belt on. You're like, "Cool.
Maybe I could do software as a service,"
which could be a lead magnet, which you
could say a calorie calculator
is like that for the PT. You're like,
"Cool.
I'm going to do a webinar where we're
going to go in on a specific topic." What
topic do you talk about?
Maybe the one on the video
that you've done that's got the
most views.
Maybe another type of lead magnet could be
a prompt for AI.
It could be how to put together a highly
converting landing page, which I'll put a
link to the description to download that.
You can pull lead magnets out of a bloody
hat like a magician
pulling rabbits out. As long as you
are well-connected with your audience
and you
understand their pains, problems, fears,
insecurities, and issues that they have on
a daily basis. Now, if you put
that into a webinar,
here's the beautiful part,
brother. So I did
that two hour 20 recording. Get home.
Then what?
You're probably thinking, "Oh my God,
am I Chris Williamson?" Okay,
I'm going to go
to my studio for a second.
I know you can't see this, Declan, but
hopefully they will believe me. Okay.
That webinar was 138 days ago. 138.
Since posting it, 8,000 views, of
which 19 views
in the last 48 hours.
Call it 10 views a day.
Now,
10 views a day doesn't seem like a lot,
but the average view duration is 19
minutes 40. 19 minutes 40. So that's
194 minutes of that webinar getting
absorbed a
day. That is a lot
when you think about it.
So I got the people on the webinar,
I got to convert people on the webinar,
I got
the email addresses of the people
that didn't turn up.
I then could post it as its own video on
YouTube, and it now sits
there getting 10 people to watch 19
minutes a day.
As far as effort in and the reward back,
it is one of the easiest
things you can do to benefit your
ecosystem of converting people
to becoming high-paying clients, which
is something you just shouldn't
sleep on. Now,
I know this isn't a webinar.
This is a video that's probably about 13
minutes long.
But this is just one of the many things
that I teach people inside my mentorship.
If you're thinking about working with me,
you should. I can't do this forever.
NewTonic is getting too big too fast.
I think it's a very good deal for access
to me, my amazing coaches, and
community.
So if you're watching this video,
if you join with the link in the
description,
if within three months you haven't seen a
meaningful change to your
business, email me, james@newtonic.com.
We can hash it out.
Because ultimately,
if you're ambitious
and you genuinely want to do better in
business with your personal brand,
whatever it is you're doing,
this should work.
And if it doesn't,
I'll take responsibility for that.
If you can come to me with receipts
and go, "James,
I've done what you told me.
Here's a stack of proof
that it didn't work," you should have your
money back.
But for the majority of people,
this shit works.
So link's in the description.
Get stuck into it.
If you're not interested in giving me your
money today, I'll
wear you down, brother.
I'll wear you down.
I'll turn up here all the time.
But until then, there's a video here
that YouTube recommends you watch.
So get stuck into that.